Tangible problems.
世上有很多显而易见的问题。
I always felt from as long as I can remember about the power of science,
我从开始认知到现在一直感觉，用科学的力量
that it could be used to solve pressing issues, solve problems.
可以来解决各种迫切的问题。
When I studied Chemistry at Princeton it was so theoretical, unapplied.
但我在普林斯顿大学化学专业学习的时候，感觉这个学科太理论化，应用性不强。
And I thought oh ok, maybe if I go into physics it will get better.
于是我想，哦，好吧，没准物理学会更实际点，干脆改专业吧
So I did, and was grossly disappointed.
于是我改成了物理专业，但结果还是大失所望。
We were studying wave propagation, and I couldn't understand this one problem, this one equation.
当时我们研究波传播，有这么一个公式我总弄不明白，
So I went to the professor and I said whats this about, where does this exist?
于是我去问教授，这公式到底是怎么回事，是怎么得出的？
And he said well it actually doesn't exist, I just made it up.
他回答说，其实这公式是我自己造出来的。
It's like, oh ok, so that's what we do here.
我当时愣了，然后恍然大悟，心想，太离谱了吧，我们竟然可以自己造公式！
That was one of those turning points where I said, wow what am I doing here?
对我来说这是一个转折点，我开始反思自己在这儿到底在做什么。
In an absolute abundance of resources, power,
虽然我们有取之不尽用之不竭的资源、能量，
human development and culture and everything,
我们人类文明有了那么大的进步，
still there's many issues. Mainly the resource conflicts. Poverty, war, depravation.
很多问题依然存在。而这些问题的本质在于资源分配的矛盾。资源的不均导致贫穷、战争、人性的堕落。
Survival with the awesome technology that we do have today?
生存，在我们这个高科技的时代，
Survival should not take a lot of time.
应该不是个难题。
When you really think about it, all the wealth that we enjoy today for a modern standard of living
如果你仔细想想，我们今天现代化的生活方式所依赖的资源，
relies on rocks, soil, sunlight, plants, water.
不外乎矿产、土壤、阳光、植被和水。
Those are all abundant.
这些资源几乎是取之不尽用之不竭的。
Yet the productive mechanism of society is what makes it scarce, artificially so.
然而当代社会的生产机制人为的使这些资源变得匮乏。
What if we could survive and thrive up to a modern standard of living,
有没有一种方法，让我们每天只工作两小时，利用当地的资源，
and not only that, at two hours a day of work, and from local resources.
不仅能生存下来，还能达到现代化的生活标准。
How would that be?
这种方法会是怎样的呢？
The most important part of Open Source Ecology is this idea that
方法就是我们所说的“开源生态系统”。它的核心思想就是，
with a small amount of resources and a small amount of money,
依赖少量的资源和金钱，
anybody should be able to create a high standard of living for themselves,
任何人都能够实现高质量的生活标准。
and do it in a way that doesn't require a whole lot of time, a whole lot of money.
这种方法不需要花费大量的时间和金钱上的投资。
People can actually be empowered by the technology we're creating here,
我们创造的这种技术其实可以让人们更加自立自强，
so rather than a big corporation deciding what machines can do for us,
与其让一个大企业决定用机器为我们生产什么产品，
we can decide how we want machines to work for us.
我们完全可以自己决定。
Instead of relying on other people to make things that we need,
与其依赖别人为我们制造所需的东西，
we can make everything that we need for ourselves.
我们完全可以自己动手DIY，
And we can do it better than Walmart can do it,
而且我们自己做的要比沃尔玛做的好的多。
we can do it better than slave labour in China can do it.
我们自己做的，要比中国的廉价劳动力做的好的多。
We can make the productive capacity that we need to live the lives that we want
在我们自家的后院里，我们完全有能力动手实现我们所需的生活方式，
in our own back yards, and we can do it in a sustainable way.
而且这种方法是可持续性的。
We can make machines that we can use to create material abundance for ourselves,
我们可以动手制作机器，提供给我们所需要的丰富材料。
and then we can show other people how to do it.
我们还能教别人怎么做。
If you have two-hundred people get together
假如有两百个人走到了一起，
and if they want to put together a self-sustaining community,
打算一起建设一个自给自足的社区，
they don't have many options as far as coming up with the equipment and machines for doing that.
在没有财政能力购买他们所需要的机械设备的情况下，
That's where Open Source Ecology really comes in.
我们的“开源生态系统”便有了用武之地。
The costs of building these machines is about ten percent of what you would buy it for commercially.
动手搭建系统所需的机械设备，造价仅需市场价格的十分之一。
If you take a full blown John Deere tractor,
比如“约翰·迪尔牌牵引车”，
it's almost impossible for anyone to go out and try to build one of those for themselves.
你要想自己造一架一模一样的牵引车肯定很困难，
I mean that's just a very custom machine.
因为那毕竟是高度定制的机器。
But if you're able to take off-the-shelf engines and
但如果你买那种现成的发动机，
go down to your hardware store and buy steel and build it yourself, like the Lifetrac,
再去五金店买一些钢铁，回家动手组装一台像“廉价多功能开源式牵引机”那样的机器，
then that's much more realistic.
会简单现实的多。
The benefits of a localized economy are that
本地化经济的好处便是
the power stays within the community, the economic wealth.
社区有掌控自己财权的力量
Instead of your money, the earnings, going all the way down the river,
你辛辛苦苦赚到的钱不会白白随波逐流。
what if we can internalise that?
假如我们可以通过在社区内建立一种生产机制
Keep that wealth in,
使财富敛聚于社区内不外流，
by having all that productive mechanism built in.
使财富在社区内流动，
You produce the same, the wealth stays in, you don't have to work so hard.
你的劳动产出还是一样，你赚得的财富将流通于社区内，你将不必那么辛苦的工作。
Then you can have time for you family and kids, or whatever else is more important to you.
你将有充足的时间陪家人孩子，做自己喜欢的事。
So it's a lot easier productionwise to just have one super compatible module.
综上所述，“开源式生态系统”这种超级兼容的模块化生产能极大的提高生产效率。
The Powercube right now works with both the Lifetrac and the CEB Press,
“Powercube液压动力引擎“目前应用于Lifetrac牵引机和CEB压力机，
and a few other machines we have, like the Ironworker and the Coldsaw.
以及我们开发的其他几种机器，如Ironworker打孔机和Coldsaw锯床。
So that provides a much simpler product ecology
这提供了一种极为简单的产品生态系统：
because one power unit serves multiple machines.
一种动力装置服务于多台机器。
There is one thing about just being able to look at machines that have been developed on site here,
我们不仅能现场目睹机器设备的开发，
and another thing to understand how the development process went through and
还能了解整个的生产过程，
what kind of documentation there is for these machines,
阅读各种机器设备的说明文件，
such that can be replicated and improved on.
这些文件可以被复制和改进。
Fortunately we have that ability to have machine information in the digital format,
幸运的是我们已经可以将机器信息数字化，
and now we have telecom, the Internet, to relay that information and
并可以通过电信和互联网传递这些信息
have anyone just copy over the files,
与所有人分享
and have access to the model on their computer.
任何人都可以直接从电脑上打开这些文件。
So Open Source Ecology tries to capture the open source nature of development and the fact
因此”开源生态系统“致力于开发的开源性
that we're connected to Nature, to other people, to societal institutions.
以及我们与自然、其他人和各种社会机构的联系。
That all has to be considered if we're talking about a paradigm to make a better world.
当我们谈到一个美好世界的典范时，我们必须综合考虑各种因素。
Open source was clearly the emerging trend that was so powerful.
”开源“已悄悄成为日渐强大的趋势，
Demonstrated with open source software like the Linux platform.
从开源式软件系统Linux平台的开发就可以看出。
When a sufficient number of people come together on a project,
当一个项目汇集了够多的开发者
that project simply becomes better than anything else.
这个项目便如虎添翼，趋于臻美。
So we're transitioning that into the hardware space.
我们现在做的，就是将这个理念应用于机械设备领域。
What would happen if people actually collaborated on making open source hardware?
当人们合作共同开发开源式机械设备时，结果会是怎样的呢？
We have lots of technology out there.
我们现在拥有的技术非常繁杂，
But to organise the technology in such a way that it's accessible,
而把这些技术以一种易于访问的途径组织起来，
without barriers to people, that is a very significant move forward.
对人们来说不再成为障碍，这本身就是一个具有重要意义的进步。
Now it's there for the individuals to organise themselves,
现在轮到我们个人去组织起来，
and to really dig deeply, almost to what you would say a spiritual level.
用打破沙锅问到底的精神，或者说用一种信仰式的执着，
To really change their attitudes, and to take advantage of what is there,
来真正的改变自己的态度，用可以利用的资源，
and to move our civilisation forward.
推动我们的文明。
I'm hopeful that human kind will arise to the occasion and
我希望人类能够站起来，
seize the opportunity offered by this development.
抓住这个“开源式生态系统”带来的机会。
Open Source Ecology is really about creating the next economy: the open source economy.
这个系统的精髓在于创造下一代经济模式：开源式经济。
And what does that mean? It's an economy that optimises not only production,
开源式经济和目前的经济模式一样，
which the present economy is really good at,
擅长于优化生产系统，
it's effective in production, but distribution is not so great.
但同时它也是高效率的生产系统。唯一的缺点是分配还不算完善。
And how do you do that? And that is by opening...
那么如何完善分配过程呢？方法就是...
so called giving away trade secrets for free, or
所谓的免费分享商业机密，或者说
developing open source products for just about anything that we use.
开发生产开源式产品，应用于我们生活的方方面面。
So imagine a scenario where instead of corporations all competing, reinventing the wheel and so forth,
想象一下这样的图景：公司、企业不再互相竞争，白费力气重复生产，造成大量浪费，
a lot of competitive waste, what if everyone were to join together to make the best products,
而相反，人人都团结起来创造质量最好、最稳健的产品，
the most robust products, that are open source, that anyone has access to producing them.
并且是开源的，任何人都能免费获得开源文件用来生产，
And therefore we can run an economy in a collaborative way,
这样做的结果就是，我们的经济会模式变得开源、协作，
as opposed to a competitive wasteful way.
而非竞争、浪费。
A film by Tristan Copley Smith
崔斯坦·考博雷·史密斯执导